Local 1199 Leon Davis Additional Papers 5938
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Leon Davis Additional Papers
1957-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 National Union of Health Care
Davis, Leon
5938
2.61 cubic feet
2.6 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
5736587
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 29, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4038 AV: Leon Davis Classroom Presentation Audio-Visual Materials 5206: Local 1199 Records 5206-PR: Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records 5510: Local 1199 Records 5525: Local 1199 Additional Files 5651: Local 1199 Additional Records 5854: Local 1199 Additional Records 5871: Local 1199 Additional Records 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records
Health facilities--Employees--Labor unions; Hospitals--Employees--Labor unions; Davis, Leon, 1907-; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees.; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees, Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.)--Archives.
5736587
- Files (Box 1)
  - 1199. History., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Leon. Autobiography. Transcriptions., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards and Citations., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awards and Citations., 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographies of Leon Davis. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Scope and Contents
    no date
  - Cherkasky, Martin. Retirement., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence., 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence., 1973-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence. Leon Davis in Jail, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Obituaries, Memorials, and Condolences on Death of Leon Davis., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Beth-El Hospital Strike. Scrapbook., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Upheaval in the Quiet Zone." Reviews., 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Awards and Citations., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles by Davis and Foner (Box 1)
  - "Low on the Totem Pole," IUD Digest., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "A Jewish Labor Leader Speaks," Jewish Currents., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Of Jews and Black Workers," Jewish Digest., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Leon Davis Interviews (Box 1)
  - "Images of Labor At Gallery 1199," Labor's Heritage., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "A National Hospital Union?" Hospital World., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Settlement or Strike," Food Management., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Leon Davis In First Person: An Oral History," Hospital Administration Oral History Collection, Lewis E. Weeks Series., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 1199 Publications (Box 1)
  - 1199 Drug News. Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Issue., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1199 News. Working in Hospitals: Then and Now., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bread and Roses: A Special Report., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Working American., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1199 News. Lawrence 1912: The Bread and Roses Strike., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Images of Labor., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Images of Labor. Discussion Guide., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Everything's Coming Up Bread and Roses: A Progress Report., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1199 News. "Leon Davis: His Passion for Justice Built a Union", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1199 News., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1199 News., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Talking With My Feet. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Dr. King's American Dream: Keep It Alive. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Articles about 1199 and Davis (Box 1)
  - "An Organizer of the Underprivileged," Fortune., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "A Union With 'Soul'," New York Times Magazine., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Coalition," Coalition News., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "'Turnergate' At 1199: A Union Divided Against Itself," The Nation., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Labor Pains," New York., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Hospital Suit Puts Union in a Fit," Daily News., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "RWDSU: 50 Years of History, 50 Years of the Good Fight." RWDSU Record., 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dubin, Marshall. "1199: The Bread and Roses Union.", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Leon Davis and Martin Luther King Honored by Pharmacy Union," Spotlight., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Audio-Visual (Box 2)
  - Vinyl Audio Record. The Union Democracy Built., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Memorabilia (Box 2)
  - Pin. Local 1199. 25 Years. AFL-CIO, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pin. National Hospital Union. 1199. RWDSU AFL/CIO (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Flag. Solidarity. 1199. National Hospital Union. Health Care For All. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cork Press. Cast Iron. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Photographs (Box 3)
  - Broadside (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 6)